My name is Joseph Shung Chiang Lee.
I am a member of the Calcutta Racing Pigeon Club.
This ring that you can see is not made in India.
They are imported from Belgium.
We import the ring from Belgium to prevent anyone from duplicating the ring.
So this is why any people are making the same number of rings.
So this ring is made with aluminum metal ring and the people would just bring the number and the club name and the year and then covered with plastic.
Now this ring is released from the club but 2007 ring is given from the club only after December 1, 2006 and the ring you have to put on the ring on the youngster when they are only about 7 days old.
More than 7 days old then the leg will become sore and it would be difficult to put the ring in.
This pigeon is about more than 2 weeks old and you can see it is impossible to take out the ring or to put in another ring without injuring the leg of the bird.
So once this pigeon has grown to become an adult pigeon, you cannot remove the ring.
Neither you can put on any other ring.
So this number belongs to this pigeon; it cannot be changed.